MARAT FAKHREEV

FRONT-END ENGINEER

Kazan, Russia +7 (951) 891-72-33 Barcelona, Spain +34 686 759 768

maratfakhreev.com marat.fakhreev@gmail.com github.com/maratfakhreev linkedin.com/in/maratfakhreev

PROFILE

I'm front-end engineer with more than 10 years experience. I'm into the modern JavaScript stack and everything related to web, desktop, and mobile technologies built with it. I try to be a perfectionist in everything I do, pay attention to details in any UI/UX solution. I like writing both useful and not too much code in my free time. Take a moment to explore crazy and demanded things from the programming world and the real world as well. Love industrial design, art, music, motorsport and wine tasting.

EXPERIENCE

FRONT-END STAFF ENGINEER, BIRCH, USA, 2024-PRESENT

I've been responsible for the architecture and features development across several products. There are sophisticated infrastructure application for advertising teams and the application that helps manage the creative workflow for creative teams. Core technologies: TypeScript, React, Vue, Vite, Go, Ruby on Rails.

FRONT-END LEAD ENGINEER, REVEALBOT, USA, 2018-2024

I was responsible for the development of the architecture and final features in main client. This client is part of huge distributed application that provides convenient tools that automate ad management strategies, launch new ad companies with bunch of variations and analyze insights based on current working process. All of this are for popular ad platforms such Facebook/Google/TikTok etc. The distinctive feature of the app without exaggeration is the best UI/UX in industry which also competitors try and most often fail to copy:). Core technologies: Vue, JSX, CSS-in-JS, Webpacker, Ruby on Rails.

BROWSER EXTENSION/MOBILE APP ENGINEER, MAYAK, RUSSIA, 2020-2024

Part time/on demand experience in one of the leading marketplaces analytics service in Russia. I've launched and fully developed chrome extension with more than 400k users and mobile application companion (iOS/Android) which embed detailed statistic

for different sellers, brands and goods right in the marketplaces pages. The main goal was to create super fast thin and responsive part of product that essentially brings the user to the main part of the service. Browser extension technologies: Vanilla javascript, Preact, Gulp. Mobile app technologies: Expo, React Native.

FRONT-END ENGINEER, CINARRA SYSTEMS, RUSSIA, 2017-2018

I was responsible for front-end part of huge RTB application. This part allows clients to form an advertising company, specify the target audience and also monitor its effectiveness on the basis of multiple metrics. Core technologies: React, Redux, Recompose and other FP stuff.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER/LEAD DEVELOPER, FLATSTACK, RUSSIA, 2013-2017

I was responsible for front-end part of different projects with different complexity and field of activity. Here at different time I was a part of 3-10 people size teams which provide full development cycle. I've tried popular FE-frameworks like React, Angular, Backbone/Marionette, also gained experience in varying degrees with technologies such as Node.js on BE, Cordova/Phonegap as mobile framework.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER, DARING AND YOUNG, RUSSIA, 2012-2013 I was responsible for front-end work of websites. Most projects were on Backbone.js and jQuery. Was mostly focused on interface markup and animation.

EDUCATION

Master's degree in computer science - Kazan State University, 2013-2015 Bachelor's degree in computer science - Kazan State University, 2009-2013 Languages: Russian (native), English (b2), Spanish (basic)

SKILLS

<u>Architecture</u>: Micro frontend, Unidirectional architectures, Functional Programming, Module & MVC architectures, OOP, KISS principles.

<u>UI Development</u>: HTML, CSS, CSS-in-JS, Pre/Post processors, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Preact, Vue, Backbone/Marionette

<u>Data management</u>: Zustand, Redux, Vuex, Flux

Networking: Node.js, REST, JSON-API, SSE

<u>Dev environment & deployment</u>: Vite, Esbuild, Webpack, Browserify, Gulp, Docker, Ansible,

Mobile and desktop development: Expo, React Native, Cordova, Electron

Other: Chrome extensions API, Messengers API, Web scraping

OPEN SOURCE

React-base (http://github.com/fs/react-base)

React hot loader (https://github.com/gaearon/react-hot-loader)

Marionette.js (https://github.com/marionettejs/backbone.marionette)

Handlebars web pack plugin (https://github.com/sagold/handlebars-webpack-plugin)

Backbone-base (https://github.com/fs/backbone-base)

Backbone ES6 Promise (https://github.com/maratfakhreev/backbone-es6-promise)

Marionette Animated Region (https://github.com/maratfakhreev/marionette-animated-region)

Marionette Routes Helper (https://github.com/maratfakhreev/marionette-routes-helper)

Node telegram random message replier (https://github.com/maratfakhreev/node-telegram-random-message-replier)

PET PROJECTS

Telegra.ph media downloader (https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/telegraph-media-downloade/nblopllhhljcbkjokcgcgakmilehpedp?utm_source=item-share-cb)

<u>About</u>: Browser extension that allows to download images, videos, and audio from Telegra.ph.

Role: Browser extension developer.

Stack: TypeScript, Gulp.

DailySheet (daily-dev.com)

About: Desktop app that aggregates tech news and feeds

Role: Client app developer, website developer.

Stack: Electron, Typescript, React, Styled components, Webpack, Ansible.